<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
<records>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>840</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Baldry, I.~K.</author><author>Land, K.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.~S.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Torki, M.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Edmondson, E.~M.</author><author>Miller, C.~J.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: the dependence of morphology and colour on environment</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>393</volume><pages>1324-1352</pages><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>March</date></pub-dates></dates><label>bam09</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: clusters: general , galaxies: evolution , galaxies: fundamental parameters , galaxies: statistics , galaxies: structure</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/bamford2009a.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2008.14252.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We analyse the relationships between galaxy morphology, colour, environment and stellar mass using data for over 105 objects from Galaxy Zoo, the largest sample of visually classified morphologies yet compiled. We conclusively show that colour and morphology fractions are very different functions of environment. Both colour and morphology are sensitive to stellar mass. However, at fixed stellar mass, while colour is also highly sensitive to environment, morphology displays much weaker environmental trends. Only a small part of both the morphology-density and colour-density relations can be attributed to the variation in the stellar-mass function with environment.  Galaxies with high stellar masses are mostly red in all environments and irrespective of their morphology. Low stellar-mass galaxies are mostly blue in low-density environments, but mostly red in high-density environments, again irrespective of their morphology. While galaxies with early-type morphology do always have higher red fractions, this is subdominant compared to the dependence of red fraction on stellar mass and environment. The colour-density relation is primarily driven by variations in colour fractions at fixed morphology, in particular the fraction of spiral galaxies that have red colours, and especially at low stellar masses. We demonstrate that our red spirals primarily include galaxies with true spiral morphology, and that they constitute an additional population to the S0 galaxies considered by previous studies. We clearly show there is an environmental dependence for colour beyond that for morphology. The environmental transformation of galaxies from blue to red must occur on significantly shorter time-scales than the transformation from spiral to early-type.  We also present many of our results as functions of the distance to the nearest galaxy group. This confirms that the environmental trends we present are not specific to the manner in which environment is quantified, but nevertheless provides plain evidence for an environmental process at work in groups. However, the properties of group members show little dependence on the total mass of the group they inhabit, at least for group masses .  Before using the Galaxy Zoo morphologies to produce the above results, we first quantify a luminosity-, size- and redshift-dependent classification bias that affects this data set, and probably most other studies of galaxy population morphology. A correction for this bias is derived and applied to produce a sample of galaxies with reliable morphological-type likelihoods, on which we base our analysis.  This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 100, 000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/Volunteers.aspx  E-mail: steven.bamford@nottingham.ac.uk</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/06/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>523</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Banerji, M.</author><author>Lahav, O.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Abdalla, F.~B.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: reproducing galaxy morphologies via machine learning</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>406</volume><pages>342-353</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>July</date></pub-dates></dates><label>ban10</label><keywords><keyword>methods: data analysis, galaxies: general</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/banerji2010.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.16713.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.16713.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present morphological classifications obtained using machine learning for objects in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey DR6 that have been classified by Galaxy Zoo into three classes, namely early types, spirals and point sources/artefacts. An artificial neural network is trained on a subset of objects classified by the human eye, and we test whether the machine-learning algorithm can reproduce the human classifications for the rest of the sample. We find that the success of the neural network in matching the human classifications depends crucially on the set of input parameters chosen for the machine-learning algorithm. The colours and parameters associated with profile fitting are reasonable in separating the objects into three classes. However, these results are considerably improved when adding adaptive shape parameters as well as concentration and texture. The adaptive moments, concentration and texture parameters alone cannot distinguish between early type galaxies and the point sources/artefacts. Using a set of 12 parameters, the neural network is able to reproduce the human classifications to better than 90 per cent for all three morphological classes. We find that using a training set that is incomplete in magnitude does not degrade our results given our particular choice of the input parameters to the network. We conclude that it is promising to use machine-learning algorithms to perform morphological classification for the next generation of wide-field imaging surveys and that the Galaxy Zoo catalogue provides an invaluable training set for such purposes.  This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 100000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/Volunteers.aspx.  E-mail: mbanerji@ast.cam.ac.uk ‡  Einstein Fellow.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>11</rec-number><ref-type>47</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Borden, K.~A.</author><author>Kapadia, A.</author><author>Smith, A.</author><author>Whyte, L.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Barnes, J.</author><author>Shupla, C.</author><author>Manning, J.~G.</author><author>Gibbs, M.~G.</author></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Educational Exploration of the Zooniverse: Tools for Formal and Informal Audience Engagement</title><secondary-title>Communicating Science: A National Conference on Science Education and Public Outreach</secondary-title><tertiary-title>Astronomical Society of the Pacific Conference Series</tertiary-title></titles><volume>473</volume><pages>101</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>April</date></pub-dates></dates><label>bor13</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/borden2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013ASPC..473..101B</url></related-urls></urls><abstract>The Zooniverse is a collection of online citizen science projects with over 600,000 volunteers worldwide.  With more than thirty peer-reviewed academic publications across ten projects, the Zooniverse is firmly established as a tool for researchers.  Zooniverse volunteers participate in a variety of scientific tasks ranging from galaxy classification (Galaxy Zoo) to the transcription of ancient Greek papyri (Ancient Lives), demonstrating that citizen science is applicable to a diverse range of research fields. While they were not primarily conceived as such, the accessible nature of the Zooniverse projects makes them a valuable tool for scientific outreach.  After all, what better way to communicate science than to ask people to contribute to research?  In this session Zooniverse developers and educators demonstrated educational resources complementing Zooniverse projects for informal learning audiences, formal learning audiences and Zooniverse volunteers.</abstract><custom3>inproceedings</custom3><added-date>25/10/2013</added-date><modified-date>25/10/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>768</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cardamone, C.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Sarzi, M.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Bennert, N.</author><author>Urry, C.~M.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Parejko, J.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo Green Peas: discovery of a class of compact extremely star-forming galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>399</volume><pages>1191-1205</pages><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>November</date></pub-dates></dates><label>car09</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: dwarf , galaxies: evolution , galaxies: formation , galaxies: high-redshift , galaxies: Seyfert , galaxies: starburst</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/cardamone2009.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2009.15383.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We investigate a class of rapidly growing emission line galaxies, known as `Green Peas&apos;, first noted by volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project because of their peculiar bright green colour and small size, unresolved in Sloan Digital Sky Survey imaging. Their appearance is due to very strong optical emission lines, namely [OIII] lambda5007Å, with an unusually large equivalent width of up to ~1000Å. We discuss a well-defined sample of 251 colour-selected objects, most of which are strongly star forming, although there are some active galactic nuclei interlopers including eight newly discovered narrow-line Seyfert 1 galaxies. The star-forming Peas are low-mass galaxies (M ~ 108.5-1010Msolar) with high star formation rates (~10Msolaryr-1), low metallicities (log[O/H] + 12 ~ 8.7) and low reddening [E(B - V) &lt;= 0.25] and they reside in low-density environments. They have some of the highest specific star formation rates (up to ~10-8yr-1) seen in the local Universe, yielding doubling times for their stellar mass of hundreds of Myr. The few star-forming Peas with Hubble Space Telescope imaging appear to have several clumps of bright star-forming regions and low surface density features that may indicate recent or ongoing mergers. The Peas are similar in size, mass, luminosity and metallicity to luminous blue compact galaxies. They are also similar to high-redshift ultraviolet-luminous galaxies, e.g. Lyman-break galaxies and Lyalpha emitters, and therefore provide a local laboratory with which to study the extreme star formation processes that occur in high-redshift galaxies. Studying starbursting galaxies as a function of redshift is essential to understanding the build up of stellar mass in the Universe.  This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 200000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/Volunteers.aspx  E-mail: ccardamone@astro.yale.edu</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>09/11/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>549</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Carpineti, A.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Darg, D.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Shabala, S.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Spheroidal post-mergers in the local Universe</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>420</volume><pages>2139-2146</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>March</date></pub-dates></dates><label>car12</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, cD, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: formation, galaxies: interactions</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/carpineti2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.20179.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.20179.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Galaxy merging is a fundamental aspect of the standard hierarchical galaxy formation paradigm. Recently, the Galaxy Zoo project has compiled a large, homogeneous catalogue of 3373 mergers, through direct visual inspection of the entire Sloan Digital Sky Survey spectroscopic sample. We explore a subset of galaxies from this catalogue that are spheroidal &apos;post-mergers&apos; (SPMs) - where a single remnant is in the final stages of relaxation after the merger and shows evidence for a dominant bulge, making them plausible progenitors of early-type galaxies. Our results indicate that the SPMs have bluer colours than the general early-type galaxy population possibly due to merger-induced star formation. An analysis using optical emission-line ratios indicates that 20 of our SPMs exhibit LINER or Seyfert-like activity (68 per cent), while the remaining 10 galaxies are classified as either star forming (16 per cent) or quiescent (16 per cent). A comparison to the emission-line activity in the ongoing mergers from Darg et al. indicates that the active galactic nuclei (AGN) fraction rises in the post-mergers, suggesting that the AGN phase probably becomes dominant only in the very final stages of the merger process. The optical colours of the SPMs and the plausible mass ratios for their progenitors indicate that, while a minority are consistent with major mergers between two early-type galaxies, the vast majority are remnants of major mergers where at least one progenitor is a late-type galaxy.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>12/10/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>490</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Casteels, K.~R.~V.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Skibba, R.~A.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Smith, A.~M.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: quantifying morphological indicators of galaxy interaction</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>429</volume><pages>1051-1065</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>February</date></pub-dates></dates><label>cas13</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: evolution, galaxies: general, galaxies: interactions, galaxies: structure</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/casteels2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/mnras/sts391</electronic-resource-num><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>26/02/2013</added-date><modified-date>26/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>686</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Chakraborti, S.</author><author>Yadav, N.</author><author>Cardamone, C.</author><author>Ray, A.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Radio Detection of Green Peas: Implications for Magnetic Fields in Young Galaxies</title><secondary-title>\apjl</secondary-title></titles><volume>746</volume><pages>L6</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>February</date></pub-dates></dates><label>cha12</label><keywords><keyword>cosmic rays, galaxies: magnetic fields, galaxies: starburst, radio continuum: galaxies</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/chakraborti2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/2041-8205/746/1/L6</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/2041-8205/746/1/L6</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Green Peas are a new class of young, emission line galaxies that were discovered by citizen volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their low stellar mass, low metallicity, and very high star formation rates make Green Peas the nearby (z ~ 0.2) analogs of the Lyman break galaxies which account for the bulk of the star formation in the early universe (z ~ 2-5). They thus provide accessible laboratories in the nearby universe for understanding star formation, supernova feedback, particle acceleration, and magnetic field amplification in early galaxies. We report the first direct radio detection of Green Peas with low frequency Giant Metrewave Radio Telescope observations and our stacking detection with archival Very Large Array FIRST data. We show that the radio emission implies that these extremely young galaxies already have magnetic fields (gsim 30 muG) even larger than that of the Milky Way. This is at odds with the present understanding of magnetic field growth based on amplification of seed fields by dynamo action over a galaxy&apos;s lifetime. Our observations strongly favor models with pregalactic magnetic fields at muG levels.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>02/05/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>30</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cheung, E.</author><author>Athanassoula, L.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Bosma, A.</author><author>Bell, E.~F.</author><author>Faber, S.~M.</author><author>Koo, D.~C.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Melvin, T.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Skibba, R.~A.</author><author>Willett, K.~W.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: Observing Secular Evolution Through Bars</title><secondary-title>ArXiv e-prints</secondary-title></titles><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>October</date></pub-dates></dates><label>che13</label><keywords><keyword>Astrophysics - Cosmology and Extragalactic Astrophysics</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/cheung2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1310.2941</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013arXiv1310.2941C</url></related-urls></urls><abstract>Observations have shown that there is a connection between the presence of a bar and the properties of a galaxy. In a parallel effort, simulations have shown that this connection is consistent with the theory of bar-driven secular evolution. But observational evidence of bar-driven secular evolution has been sparse. In this paper, we use the Galaxy Zoo 2 dataset to look for evidence of this secular evolution. Our sample consists of 13,295 disk galaxies, with an overall bar fraction of 23.6 +/- 0.4%, of which 1,154 barred galaxies also have bar length measurements. These samples are the largest ever used to study the role of bars in disk galaxy evolution. We characterize bars by the bar likelihood, the likelihood a bar is present in a given galaxy, and the bar length. These two bar properties show interesting correlations with the specific star formation rate and the inner central structure of galaxies. Comparing these observations to state-of-the-art simulations of bar evolution, which include live halos and the effects of gas and star formation, reveals that these trends are consistent with the predicted effects of gas content and bulges on bar formation and evolution. These results represent empirical evidence for secular evolution driven by bars in disk galaxies. This work suggests that bars are not stagnant structures within disk galaxies, but are a critical evolutionary driver of their host galaxies in the local universe (z &lt; 1).</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>14/10/2013</added-date><modified-date>14/10/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>837</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Clery, Daniel</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo Volunteers Share Pain and Glory of Research</title><secondary-title>Science</secondary-title></titles><volume>333</volume><number>6039</number><pages>173-175</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates></pub-dates></dates><label>cle11</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/clery2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.333.6039.173</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1126/science.333.6039.173</electronic-resource-num><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>12/07/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>585</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cortese, L.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Are passive red spirals truly passive?. The current star formation activity of optically red disc galaxies</title><secondary-title>\aap</secondary-title></titles><volume>543</volume><pages>A132</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>July</date></pub-dates></dates><label>cor12</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: evolution, galaxies: photometry, galaxies: star formation, ultraviolet: galaxies, infrared: galaxies</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/cortese2012a.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1051/0004-6361/201219443</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We used GALEX ultraviolet and WISE 22 mum observations to investigate the current star formation activity of the optically red spirals recently identified as part of the Galaxy Zoo project. These galaxies were accurately selected from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey as pure discs with low or no current star formation activity, representing one of the best optically selected samples of candidate passive spirals. However, we show that these galaxies are not only still forming stars at a significant rate (≳1 M&amp;sun; yr-1) but, more importantly, their star formation activity is not different from that of normal star-forming discs of the same stellar mass (M* ≳ 1010.2 M&amp;sun;). Indeed, these systems lie on the UV-optical blue sequence, even without any corrections for internal dust attenuation, and they follow the same specific star formation rate vs. stellar mass relation of star-forming galaxies. Our findings clearly show that at high stellar masses, optical colours do not allow to distinguish between actively star-forming and truly quiescent systems.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>12/10/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>804</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Darg, D.~W.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Sarzi, M.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Silk, J.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.~S.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: the properties of merging galaxies in the nearby Universe - local environments, colours, masses, star formation rates and AGN activity</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>401</volume><pages>1552-1563</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>January</date></pub-dates></dates><label>dar10</label><keywords><keyword>catalogues, galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, cD, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: general, galaxies: interactions, galaxies: spiral</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/darg2010.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2009.15786.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Following the study of Darg et al., we explore the environments, optical colours, stellar masses, star formation and active galactic nucleus activity in a sample of 3003 pairs of merging galaxies drawn from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey using visual classifications from the Galaxy Zoo project. While Darg et al. found that the spiral-to-elliptical ratio in (major) mergers appeared higher than that of the global galaxy population, no significant differences are found between the environmental distributions of mergers and a randomly selected control sample. This makes the high occurrence of spirals in mergers unlikely to be an environmental effect and must therefore arise from differing time-scales of detectability for spirals and ellipticals. We find that merging galaxies have a wider spread in colour than the global galaxy population, with a significant blue tail resulting from intense star formation in spiral mergers. Galaxies classed as star-forming using their emission-line properties have average star formation rates approximately doubled by the merger process though star formation is negligibly enhanced in merging elliptical galaxies. We conclude that the internal properties of galaxies significantly affect the time-scales over which merging systems can be detected (as suggested by recent theoretical studies) which leads to spirals being `over-observed&apos; in mergers. We also suggest that the transition mass 3 × 1010Msolar, noted by Kauffmann et al., below which ellipticals are rare could be linked to disc survival/destruction in mergers.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>25/07/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>522</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Darg, D.~W.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Sarzi, M.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Silk, J.</author><author>Proctor, R.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.~S.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: the fraction of merging galaxies in the SDSS and their morphologies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>401</volume><pages>1043-1056</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>January</date></pub-dates></dates><label>dar10a</label><keywords><keyword>catalogues, galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, cD, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: general, galaxies: interactions, galaxies: spiral</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/darg2010a.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2009.15686.x</electronic-resource-num><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>758</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Darg, D.~W.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Silk, J.</author><author>Lynn, S.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: multimergers and the Millennium Simulation</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>416</volume><pages>1745-1755</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates><date>September</date></pub-dates></dates><label>dar11b</label><keywords><keyword>catalogues, galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, cD, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: general, galaxies: interactions, galaxies: spiral</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/darg2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.18964.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.18964.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present a catalogue of 39 multiple mergers, found using the mergers catalogue of the Galaxy Zoo project for z &lt; 0.1, and compare them to corresponding semi-analytical galaxies from the Millennium Simulation. We estimate the (volume-limited) multimerger fraction of the local Universe using our sample and find it to be at least 2 orders of magnitude less than binary mergers - in good agreement with the simulations (especially the Munich group). We then investigate the properties of galaxies in binary mergers and multimergers (morphologies, colours, stellar masses and environment) and compare these results with those predicted by the semi-analytical galaxies. We find that multimergers favour galaxies with properties typical of elliptical morphologies and that this is in qualitative agreement with the models. Studies of multimergers thus provide an independent (and largely corroborating) test of the Millennium semi-analytical models.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>01/12/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>529</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Davis, C.~J.</author><author>Davies, J.~A.</author><author>St Cyr, O.~C.</author><author>Campbell-Brown, M.</author><author>Skelt, A.</author><author>Kaiser, M.</author><author>Meyer-Vernet, N.</author><author>Crothers, S.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Smith, A.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Baeten, E.~M.~L.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>The distribution of interplanetary dust between 0.96 and 1.04 au as inferred from impacts on the STEREO spacecraft observed by the heliospheric imagers</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>420</volume><pages>1355-1366</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>February</date></pub-dates></dates><label>dav12</label><keywords><keyword>Sun: heliosphere, solar-terrestrial relations, meteorites, meteors, meteoroids, zodiacal dust</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/davis2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.20125.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The distribution of dust in the ecliptic plane between 0.96 and 1.04 au has been inferred from impacts on the two Solar Terrestrial Relations Observatory (STEREO) spacecraft through observation of secondary particle trails and unexpected off-points in the heliospheric imager (HI) cameras. This study made use of analysis carried out by members of a distributed web-based citizen science project Solar Stormwatch. A comparison between observations of the brightest particle trails and a survey of fainter trails shows consistent distributions. While there is no obvious correlation between this distribution and the occurrence of individual meteor streams at Earth, there are some broad longitudinal features in these distributions that are also observed in sources of the sporadic meteor population. The different position of the HI instrument on the two STEREO spacecraft leads to each sampling different populations of dust particles. The asymmetry in the number of trails seen by each spacecraft and the fact that there are many more unexpected off-points in the HI-B than in HI-A indicates that the majority of impacts are coming from the apex direction. For impacts causing off-points in the HI-B camera, these dust particles are estimated to have masses in excess of 10-17 kg with radii exceeding 0.1 mum.  For off-points observed in the HI-A images, which can only have been caused by particles travelling from the anti-apex direction, the distribution is consistent with that of secondary &apos;storm&apos; trails observed by HI-B, providing evidence that these trails also result from impacts with primary particles from an anti-apex source. Investigating the mass distribution for the off-points of both HI-A and HI-B, it is apparent that the differential mass index of particles from the apex direction (causing off-points in HI-B) is consistently above 2. This indicates that the majority of the mass is within the smaller particles of this population. In contrast, the differential mass index of particles from the anti-apex direction (causing off-points in HI-A) is consistently below 2, indicating that the majority of the mass is to be found in larger particles of this distribution. This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 14 000 volunteers in the Solar Stormwatch project ().</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>2</rec-number><ref-type>47</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Eveleigh, A.</author><author>Jennett, C.</author><author>Lynn, S.</author><author>Cox, A. L.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Nacke, L. E.</author><author>Harrigan, K.</author><author>Randall, N.</author></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>“I want to be a Captain! I want to be a Captain!”: Gamification in the Old Weather Citizen Science Project</title><secondary-title>Gamification</secondary-title></titles><pages>79-82</pages><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>Oct</date></pub-dates></dates><label>eve13</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/eveleigh2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><custom3>inproceedings</custom3><added-date>29/10/2013</added-date><modified-date>29/10/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>521</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Finkelman, I.</author><author>Funes, J.~G.</author><author>Brosch, N.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Polar ring galaxies in the Galaxy Zoo</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>422</volume><pages>2386-2398</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>May</date></pub-dates></dates><label>fin12</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: peculiar</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/finkelman2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.20790.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We report observations of 16 candidate polar-ring galaxies (PRGs) identified by the Galaxy Zoo project in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) data base. Deep images of five galaxies are available in the SDSS Stripe82 data base, while to reach similar depth we observed the remaining galaxies with the 1.8-m Vatican Advanced Technology Telescope. We derive integrated magnitudes and u-r colours for the host and ring components and show continuum-subtracted Halpha+[N II] images for seven objects. We present a basic morphological and environmental analysis of the galaxies and discuss their properties in comparison with other types of early-type galaxies. Follow-up photometric and spectroscopic observations will allow a kinematic confirmation of the nature of these systems and a more detailed analysis of their stellar populations.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>495</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fischer, D.~A.</author><author>Schwamb, M.~E.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Brewer, J.</author><author>Giguere, M.</author><author>Lynn, S.</author><author>Parrish, M.</author><author>Sartori, T.</author><author>Simpson, R.</author><author>Smith, A.</author><author>Spronck, J.</author><author>Batalha, N.</author><author>Rowe, J.</author><author>Jenkins, J.</author><author>Bryson, S.</author><author>Prsa, A.</author><author>Tenenbaum, P.</author><author>Crepp, J.</author><author>Morton, T.</author><author>Howard, A.</author><author>Beleu, M.</author><author>Kaplan, Z.</author><author>Vannispen, N.</author><author>Sharzer, C.</author><author>Defouw, J.</author><author>Hajduk, A.</author><author>Neal, J.~P.</author><author>Nemec, A.</author><author>Schuepbach, N.</author><author>Zimmermann, V.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Planet Hunters: the first two planet candidates identified by the public using the Kepler public archive data</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>419</volume><pages>2900-2911</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>February</date></pub-dates></dates><label>fis12</label><keywords><keyword>stars: individual: KIC 10905746, stars: individual: KIC 6185331, planetary systems</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/fischer2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.19932.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.19932.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Planet Hunters is a new citizen science project designed to engage the public in an exoplanet search using NASA Kepler public release data. In the first month after launch, users identified two new planet candidates which survived our checks for false positives. The follow-up effort included analysis of Keck HIRES spectra of the host stars, analysis of pixel centroid offsets in the Kepler data and adaptive optics imaging at Keck using NIRC2. Spectral synthesis modelling coupled with stellar evolutionary models yields a stellar density distribution, which is used to model the transit orbit. The orbital periods of the planet candidates are 9.8844 $\pm$ 0.0087 d (KIC 10905746) and 49.7696 $\pm$ 0.000 39 d (KIC 6185331), and the modelled planet radii are 2.65 and 8.05 R⊕. The involvement of citizen scientists as part of Planet Hunters is therefore shown to be a valuable and reliable tool in exoplanet detection. This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 40 000 volunteers in the Planet Hunters project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at .</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>22/02/2013</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>447</rec-number><ref-type>5</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fortson, L.</author><author>Masters, K.</author><author>Nichol, R.</author><author>Borne, K.~D.</author><author>Edmondson, E.~M.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Raddick, J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Wallin, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Way, M.~J.</author><author>Scargle, J.~D.</author><author>Ali, K.~M.</author><author>Srivastava, A.~N.</author></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: Morphological Classification and Citizen Science</title><secondary-title>Advances in Machine Learning and Data Mining for Astronomy</secondary-title></titles><pages>213-236</pages><publisher>CRC Press, Taylor \&amp; Francis Group</publisher><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>March</date></pub-dates></dates><label>for12</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/fortson2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1104.5513</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2012amld.book..213F</url></related-urls></urls><abstract>We provide a brief overview of the Galaxy Zoo and Zooniverse projects, including a short discussion on the history of, and motivation for, these projects as well as reviewing the science these innovative Internet-based citizen science projects have produced so far. We briefly describe the method of applying en-masse human pattern recognition capabilities to complex data in data-intensive research. We also provide a discussion on the lessons learned from developing and running these community-based projects including thoughts on future applications of this methodology. This review is intended to give the reader a quick and simple introduction to the Zooniverse.</abstract><custom3>inbook</custom3><added-date>17/06/2013</added-date><modified-date>17/06/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>229</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Gies, D.~R.</author><author>Guo, Z.</author><author>Howell, S.~B.</author><author>Still, M.~D.</author><author>Boyajian, T.~S.</author><author>Hoekstra, A.~J.</author><author>Jek, K.~J.</author><author>LaCourse, D.</author><author>Winarski, T.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>KIC 9406652: An Unusual Cataclysmic Variable in the Kepler Field of View</title><secondary-title>\apj</secondary-title></titles><volume>775</volume><pages>64</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>September</date></pub-dates></dates><label>gie13</label><keywords><keyword>binaries: spectroscopic, circumstellar matter, novae, cataclysmic variables, stars: individual: KIC 9406652</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/gies2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0004-637X/775/1/64</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1308.0369</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013ApJ...775...64G</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0004-637X/775/1/64</electronic-resource-num><abstract>KIC 9406652 is a remarkable variable star in the Kepler field of view that shows both very rapid oscillations and long term outbursts in its light curve. We present an analysis of the light curve over quarters 1-15 and new spectroscopy that indicates that the object is a cataclysmic variable with an orbital period of 6.108 hr. However, an even stronger signal appears in the light curve periodogram for a shorter period of 5.753 hr, and we argue that this corresponds to the modulation of flux from the hot spot region in a tilted, precessing disk surrounding the white dwarf star. We present a preliminary orbital solution from radial velocity measurements of features from the accretion disk and the photosphere of the companion. We use a Doppler tomography algorithm to reconstruct the disk and companion spectra, and we also consider how these components contribute to the object&apos;s spectral energy distribution from ultraviolet to infrared wavelengths. This target offers us a remarkable opportunity to investigate disk processes during the high mass transfer stage of evolution in cataclysmic variables.  This work is based in part from the Planethunters.org Guest Observer program.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>02/10/2013</added-date><modified-date>02/10/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>663</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hoyle, B.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Edmondson, E.~M.</author><author>Smith, A.~M.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Scranton, R.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: bar lengths in local disc galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>415</volume><pages>3627-3640</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates><date>August</date></pub-dates></dates><label>hoy11</label><keywords><keyword>astrometry, galaxies: general</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/hoyle2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.18979.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.18979.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present an analysis of bar length measurements of 3150 local galaxies in a volume-limited sample of low-redshift (z &lt; 0.06) disc galaxies. Barred galaxies were initially selected from the Galaxy Zoo 2 project, and the lengths and widths of the bars were manually drawn by members of the Galaxy Zoo community using a Google Maps interface. Bars were measured independently by different observers, multiple times per galaxy (&gt;=3), and we find that observers were able to reproduce their own bar lengths to 3 per cent and each others&apos; to better than 20 per cent. We find a colour bimodality in our disc galaxy population with bar length, i.e. longer bars inhabit redder disc galaxies and the bars themselves are redder, and that the bluest galaxies host the smallest galactic bars (&lt;5 h-1 kpc). We also find that bar and disc colours are clearly correlated, and for galaxies with small bars, the disc is, on average, redder than the bar colours, while for longer bars the bar then itself is redder, on average, than the disc. We further find that galaxies with a prominent bulge are more likely to host longer bars than those without bulges. We categorize our galaxy populations by how the bar and/or ring are connected to the spiral arms. We find that galaxies whose bars are directly connected to the spiral arms are preferentially bluer and that these galaxies host typically shorter bars. Within the scatter, we find that stronger bars are found in galaxies which host a ring (and only a ring). The bar length and width measurements used herein are made publicly available for others to use (). This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 200 000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at .</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>26/06/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>662</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hoyle, B.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Jimenez, R.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>The fraction of early-type galaxies in low-redshift groups and clusters of galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><pages>3144</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>hoy12</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: abundances, galaxies: clusters: general, galaxies: groups: general</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/hoyle2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.21146.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.21146.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We examine the fraction of early-type (and spiral) galaxies found in groups and clusters of galaxies as a function of dark matter halo mass. We use morphological classifications from the Galaxy Zoo project matched to halo masses from both the C4 cluster catalogue and the Yang et al. group catalogue. We find that the fraction of early-type (or spiral) galaxies remains constant (changing by less than 10 per cent) over three orders of magnitude in halo mass (13 &lt;= log MH/h-1 M&amp;sun;&lt;= 15.8). This result is insensitive to our choice of halo mass measure, from velocity dispersions or summed optical luminosity. Furthermore, we consider the morphology-halo mass relations in bins of galaxy stellar mass M*, and find that while the trend of constant fraction remains unchanged, the early-type fraction amongst the most massive galaxies (11 &lt;= log M*/h-1 M&amp;sun;&lt;= 12) is a factor of 3 greater than lower mass galaxies (10 &lt;= log M*/h-1 M&amp;sun;&lt;= 10.7). We compare our observational results with those of simulations presented in De Lucia et al., as well as previous observational analyses and semi-analytic bulge (or disc) dominated galaxies from the Millennium Simulation. We find the simulations recover similar trends as observed, but may overpredict the abundances of the most massive bulge-dominated (early-type) galaxies. Our results suggest that most morphological transformation is happening on the group scale before groups merge into massive clusters. However, we show that within each halo a morphology-density relation remains: it is summing the total fraction to a self-similar scaled radius which results in a flat morphology-halo mass relationship.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>26/06/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>3</rec-number><ref-type>47</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jennett, C.</author><author>Ajani, Z.</author><author>Eveleigh, A.</author><author>Cox, A. L.</author><author>Mathieu, K.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Nacke, L. E.</author><author>Harrigan, K.</author><author>Randall, N.</author></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Creativity in Citizen Cyber-Science: All for One and One for All</title><secondary-title>WebSci</secondary-title></titles><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>May</date></pub-dates></dates><label>jen13</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/jennett2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><custom3>inproceedings</custom3><added-date>29/10/2013</added-date><modified-date>29/10/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>524</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jimenez, R.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Verde, L.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Nichol, R.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Land, K.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: a correlation between the coherence of galaxy spin chirality and star formation efficiency</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>404</volume><pages>975-980</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>May</date></pub-dates></dates><label>jim10</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: general, cosmology: theory</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/jimenez2010.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.16336.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We report on the finding of a correlation between the past star formation activity of galaxies and the degree to which the rotation axes of neighbouring galaxies are aligned. This is obtained by cross-correlating star formation histories, derived using the multiple optimized parameter estimation and data compression (MOPED) algorithm, and the spatial coherence of spin direction (chirality), as determined by the Galaxy Zoo project, for a sample of Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) galaxies. Our findings suggest that spiral galaxies, which formed the majority of their stars early (z &gt; 2), tend to display coherent rotation over scales of ~10Mpch-1. The correlation is weaker for galaxies with significant recent star formation. We find evidence for this alignment at more than the 5sigma level, but no correlation with other galaxy stellar properties. This finding can be explained within the context of hierarchical tidal-torque theory if the SDSS galaxies harbouring the majority of the old stellar population were formed in the past, in the same filament and at about the same time. Galaxies with significant recent star formation instead are in the field, thus influenced by the general tidal field that will align them in random directions, or have had a recent merger that would promote star formation but change the spin direction.  This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 100000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their individual contributions are acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/Volunteers.aspx.  E-mail: raulj@astro.princeton.edu</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>478</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Ting, Y.-S.</author><author>Bureau, M.</author><author>Shabala, S.~S.</author><author>Crockett, R.~M.</author><author>Silk, J.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Smith, A.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: dust and molecular gas in early-type galaxies with prominent dust lanes</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>423</volume><pages>49-58</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>kav12a</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, cD, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: formation, galaxies: interactions, galaxies: ISM, galaxies: peculiar</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/kaviraj2012b.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.20957.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.20957.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We explore the properties of dust and associated molecular gas in 352 nearby (0.01 &lt; z &lt; 0.07) early-type galaxies (ETGs) with prominent dust lanes, drawn from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS). Two-thirds of these &apos;dusty ETGs&apos; (D-ETGs) are morphologically disturbed, which suggests a merger origin, making these galaxies ideal test beds for studying the merger process at low redshift. The D-ETGs preferentially reside in lower density environments, compared to a control sample drawn from the general ETG population. Around 80 per cent of D-ETGs inhabit the field (compared to 60 per cent of the control ETGs) and less than 2 per cent inhabit clusters (compared to 10 per cent of the control ETGs). Compared to their control-sample counterparts, D-ETGs exhibit bluer ultraviolet-optical colours (indicating enhanced levels of star formation) and an active galactic nucleus fraction that is more than an order of magnitude greater (indicating a strikingly higher incidence of nuclear activity). The mass of clumpy dust residing in large-scale dust features is estimated, using the SDSS r-band images, to be in the range 104.5-106.5 M&amp;sun;. A comparison to the total (clumpy + diffuse) dust masses - calculated using the far-infrared fluxes of 15 per cent of the D-ETGs that are detected by the Infrared Astronomical Satellite (IRAS) - indicates that only 20 per cent of the dust is typically contained in these large-scale dust features. The dust masses are several times larger than the maximum value expected from stellar mass loss, ruling out an internal origin. The dust content shows no correlation with the blue luminosity, indicating that it is not related to a galactic scale cooling flow. Furthermore, no correlation is found with the age of the recent starburst, suggesting that the dust is accreted directly in the merger rather than being produced in situ by the triggered star formation. Using molecular gas-to-dust ratios of ETGs in the literature, we estimate that the median current molecular gas fraction in the IRAS-detected ETGs is ˜1.3 per cent. Adopting reasonable values for gas depletion time-scales and starburst ages, the median initial gas fraction in these D-ETGs is ˜4 per cent. Recent work has suggested that the merger activity in nearby ETGs largely involves minor mergers (dry ETG + gas-rich dwarf), with mass ratios between 1:10 and 1:4. If the IRAS-detected D-ETGs have formed via this channel, then the original gas fractions of the accreted satellites are between 20 and 44 per cent. This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 250 000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at .</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>25/03/2013</added-date><modified-date>25/03/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>519</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Chojnowski, S.~D.</author><author>Bennert, V.~N.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Lynn, S.</author><author>Pancoast, A.</author><author>Harris, C.</author><author>Nierenberg, A.~M.</author><author>Sonnenfeld, A.</author><author>Proctor, R.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>The Galaxy Zoo survey for giant AGN-ionized clouds: past and present black hole accretion events</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>420</volume><pages>878-900</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>February</date></pub-dates></dates><label>kee12b</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: active, galaxies: ISM, galaxies: Seyfert</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/keel2012b.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.20101.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.20101.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Some active galactic nuclei (AGN) are surrounded by extended emission-line regions (EELRs), which trace both the illumination pattern of escaping radiation and its history over the light travel time from the AGN to the gas. From a new set of such EELRs, we present evidence that the AGN in many Seyfert galaxies undergo luminous episodes 0.2-2 ? years in duration. Motivated by the discovery of the spectacular nebula known as Hanny&apos;s Voorwerp, ionized by a powerful AGN which has apparently faded dramatically within ? years, Galaxy Zoo volunteers have carried out both targeted and serendipitous searches for similar emission-line clouds around low-redshift galaxies. We present the resulting list of candidates and describe spectroscopy identifying 19 galaxies with AGN-ionized regions at projected radii ? kpc. This search recovered known EELRs (such as Mrk 78, Mrk 266 and NGC 5252) and identified additional previously unknown cases, one with detected emission to ? kpc. One new Sy 2 was identified. At least 14/19 are in interacting or merging systems, suggesting that tidal tails are a prime source of distant gas out of the galaxy plane to be ionized by an AGN. We see a mix of one- and two-sided structures, with observed cone angles from 23? to 112?. We consider the energy balance in the ionized clouds, with lower and upper bounds on ionizing luminosity from recombination and ionization-parameter arguments, and estimate the luminosity of the core from the far-infrared data. The implied ratio of ionizing radiation seen by the clouds to that emitted by the nucleus, on the assumption of a non-variable nuclear source, ranges from 0.02 to ?; 7/19 exceed unity. Small values fit well with a heavily obscured AGN in which only a small fraction of the ionizing output escapes to be traced by surrounding gas. However, large values may require that the AGN has faded over tens of thousands of years, giving us several examples of systems in which such dramatic long-period variation has occurred; this is the only current technique for addressing these time-scales in AGN history. The relative numbers of faded and non-faded objects we infer, and the projected extents of the ionized regions, give our estimate (0.2-2 ? years) for the length of individual bright phases.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>394</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Manning, A.~M.</author><author>Holwerda, B.~W.</author><author>Mezzoprete, M.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Gay, P.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: A Catalog of Overlapping Galaxy Pairs for Dust Studies</title><secondary-title>\pasp</secondary-title></titles><volume>125</volume><pages>2-16</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>January</date></pub-dates></dates><label>kee13</label><keywords><keyword>Galaxies</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/keel2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1086/669233</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1211.6723</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013PASP..125....2K</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1086/669233</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Analysis of galaxies with overlapping images offers a direct way to probe the distribution of dust extinction and its effects on the background light. We present a catalog of 1990 such galaxy pairs selected from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) by volunteers of the Galaxy Zoo project. We highlight subsamples which are particularly useful for retrieving such properties of the dust distribution as UV extinction, the extent perpendicular to the disk plane, and extinction in the inner parts of disks. The sample spans wide ranges of morphology and surface brightness, opening up the possibility of using this technique to address systematic changes in dust extinction or distribution with galaxy type. This sample will form the basis for forthcoming work on the ranges of dust distributions in local disk galaxies, both for their astrophysical implications and as the low-redshift part of a study of the evolution of dust properties. Separate lists and figures show deep overlaps, where the inner regions of the foreground galaxy are backlit, and the relatively small number of previously-known overlapping pairs outside the SDSS DR7 sky coverage.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>22/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>22/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>526</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kendrew, S.</author><author>Simpson, R.</author><author>Bressert, E.</author><author>Povich, M.~S.</author><author>Sherman, R.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Robitaille, T.~P.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Wolf-Chase, G.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>The Milky Way Project: A Statistical Study of Massive Star Formation Associated with Infrared Bubbles</title><secondary-title>\apj</secondary-title></titles><volume>755</volume><pages>71</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>August</date></pub-dates></dates><label>ken12</label><keywords><keyword>H II regions, infrared: ISM, ISM: bubbles, stars: formation, stars: massive</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/kendrew2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0004-637X/755/1/71</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The Milky Way Project citizen science initiative recently increased the number of known infrared bubbles in the inner Galactic plane by an order of magnitude compared to previous studies. We present a detailed statistical analysis of this data set with the Red MSX Source (RMS) catalog of massive young stellar sources to investigate the association of these bubbles with massive star formation. We particularly address the question of massive triggered star formation near infrared bubbles. We find a strong positional correlation of massive young stellar objects (MYSOs) and H II regions with Milky Way Project bubbles at separations of &lt;2 bubble radii. As bubble sizes increase, a statistically significant overdensity of massive young sources emerges in the region of the bubble rims, possibly indicating the occurrence of triggered star formation. Based on numbers of bubble-associated RMS sources, we find that 67% $\pm$ 3% of MYSOs and (ultra-)compact H II regions appear to be associated with a bubble. We estimate that approximately 22% $\pm$ 2% of massive young stars may have formed as a result of feedback from expanding H II regions. Using MYSO-bubble correlations, we serendipitously recovered the location of the recently discovered massive cluster Mercer 81, suggesting the potential of such analyses for discovery of heavily extincted distant clusters.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>1</rec-number><ref-type>47</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kloetzer, L.</author><author>Schneider, D.</author><author>Jennett, C.</author><author>Iacovides, I.</author><author>Eveleigh, A.</author><author>Cox, A. L.</author><author>Gold, M.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors><author>European Society for Research on the Education of Adults</author></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Learning by volunteer computing, thinking and gaming: What and how are volunteers learning by participating in Virtual Citizen Science?</title><secondary-title>7th European Research Conference</secondary-title></titles><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>Sep</date></pub-dates></dates><label>klo13</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><custom3>inproceedings</custom3><added-date>29/10/2013</added-date><modified-date>29/10/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>872</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Land, K.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Nichol, R.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: the large-scale spin statistics of spiral galaxies in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>388</volume><pages>1686-1692</pages><dates><year>2008</year><pub-dates><date>August</date></pub-dates></dates><label>lan08</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: spiral , large-scale structure of Universe</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/land2008.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2008.13490.x</electronic-resource-num><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>03/05/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>401</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Levitan, D.</author><author>Kupfer, T.</author><author>Groot, P.~J.</author><author>Kulkarni, S.~R.</author><author>Prince, T.~A.</author><author>Simonian, G.~V.</author><author>Arcavi, I.</author><author>Bloom, J.~S.</author><author>Laher, R.</author><author>Nugent, P.~E.</author><author>Ofek, E.~O.</author><author>Sesar, B.</author><author>Surace, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Five new outbursting AM CVn systems discovered by the Palomar Transient Factory</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>430</volume><pages>996-1007</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>April</date></pub-dates></dates><label>lev13</label><keywords><keyword>accretion, accretion discs, binaries: close, stars: individual: PTF1 J043517.73+002940.7, stars: individual: PTF1 J094329.59+102957.6, novae, cataclysmic variables, white dwarfs</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/levitan2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/mnras/sts672</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1212.5312</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013MNRAS.430..996L</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/mnras/sts672</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present five new outbursting AM CVn systems and one candidate discovered as part of an ongoing search for such systems using the Palomar Transient Factory (PTF). This is the first large-area, systematic search for AM CVn systems using only large-amplitude photometric variability to select candidates. Three of the confirmed systems and the candidate system were discovered as part of the PTF transient search. Two systems were found as part of a search for outbursts through the PTF photometric data base. We discuss the observed characteristics of each of these systems, including the orbital periods of two systems. We also consider the position of these systems, selected in a colour-independent survey, in colour-colour space and compare to systems selected solely by their colours. We find that the colours of our newly discovered systems do not differ significantly from those of previously known systems, but significant errors preclude a definitive answer.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>16/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>16/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>843</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Land, K.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Edmondson, E.</author><author>Masters, K.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo 1: data release of morphological classifications for nearly 900 000 galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>410</volume><pages>166-178</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates><date>January</date></pub-dates></dates><label>lin11</label><keywords><keyword>methods: data analysis, galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, cD, galaxies: general, galaxies: spiral</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/lintott2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.17432.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Morphology is a powerful indicator of a galaxy&apos;s dynamical and merger history. It is strongly correlated with many physical parameters, including mass, star formation history and the distribution of mass. The Galaxy Zoo project collected simple morphological classifications of nearly 900 000 galaxies drawn from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey, contributed by hundreds of thousands of volunteers. This large number of classifications allows us to exclude classifier error, and measure the influence of subtle biases inherent in morphological classification. This paper presents the data collected by the project, alongside measures of classification accuracy and bias. The data are now publicly available and full catalogues can be downloaded in electronic format from . This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 100 000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/06/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>706</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Land, K.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: morphologies derived from visual inspection of galaxies from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>389</volume><pages>1179-1189</pages><dates><year>2008</year><pub-dates><date>September</date></pub-dates></dates><label>lin08</label><keywords><keyword>methods: data analysis , galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, cD , galaxies: general , galaxies: spiral</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/lintott2008.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2008.13689.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2008.13689.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In order to understand the formation and subsequent evolution of galaxies one must first distinguish between the two main morphological classes of massive systems: spirals and early-type systems. This paper introduces a project, Galaxy Zoo, which provides visual morphological classifications for nearly one million galaxies, extracted from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS). This achievement was made possible by inviting the general public to visually inspect and classify these galaxies via the internet. The project has obtained more than 4 × 107 individual classifications made by ~105 participants. We discuss the motivation and strategy for this project, and detail how the classifications were performed and processed. We find that Galaxy Zoo results are consistent with those for subsets of SDSS galaxies classified by professional astronomers, thus demonstrating that our data provide a robust morphological catalogue. Obtaining morphologies by direct visual inspection avoids introducing biases associated with proxies for morphology such as colour, concentration or structural parameters. In addition, this catalogue can be used to directly compare SDSS morphologies with older data sets. The colour-magnitude diagrams for each morphological class are shown, and we illustrate how these distributions differ from those inferred using colour alone as a proxy for morphology.  This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 100000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/Volunteers.aspx  E-mail: cjl@astro.ox.ac.uk (CJL); kevins@astro.ox.ac.uk (KS)</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>12/03/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>797</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Keel, W.</author><author>van Arkel, H.</author><author>Bennert, N.</author><author>Edmondson, E.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Smith, D.~J.~B.</author><author>Herbert, P.~D.</author><author>Jarvis, M.~J.</author><author>Virani, S.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Land, K.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: `Hanny&apos;s Voorwerp&apos;, a quasar light echo?</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>399</volume><pages>129-140</pages><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>October</date></pub-dates></dates><label>lin09</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: active , galaxies: individual: IC2497 , galaxies: peculiar , quasars: general</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/lintott2009.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2009.15299.x</electronic-resource-num><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>22/08/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>402</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Schwamb, M.~E.</author><author>Barclay, T.</author><author>Sharzer, C.</author><author>Fischer, D.~A.</author><author>Brewer, J.</author><author>Giguere, M.</author><author>Lynn, S.</author><author>Parrish, M.</author><author>Batalha, N.</author><author>Bryson, S.</author><author>Jenkins, J.</author><author>Ragozzine, D.</author><author>Rowe, J.~F.</author><author>Schwainski, K.</author><author>Gagliano, R.</author><author>Gilardi, J.</author><author>Jek, K.~J.</author><author>Pääkkönen, J.-P.</author><author>Smits, T.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Planet Hunters: New Kepler Planet Candidates from Analysis of Quarter 2</title><secondary-title>\aj</secondary-title></titles><volume>145</volume><pages>151</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>lin13</label><keywords><keyword>planets and satellites: detection, planets and satellites: individual: KIC 4552729b KIC 10005758b KIC 10005758c</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/lintott2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0004-6256/145/6/151</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1202.6007</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013AJ....145..151L</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0004-6256/145/6/151</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present new planet candidates identified in NASA Kepler Quarter 2 public release data by volunteers engaged in the Planet Hunters citizen science project. The two candidates presented here survive checks for false positives, including examination of the pixel offset to constrain the possibility of a background eclipsing binary. The orbital periods of the planet candidates are 97.46 days (KIC 4552729) and 284.03 (KIC 10005758) days and the modeled planet radii are 5.3 and 3.8 R ⊕. The latter star has an additional known planet candidate with a radius of 5.05 R ⊕ and a period of 134.49 days, which was detected by the Kepler pipeline. The discovery of these candidates illustrates the value of massively distributed volunteer review of the Kepler database to recover candidates which were otherwise uncataloged.  .</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>16/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>16/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>403</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Maguire, K.</author><author>Sullivan, M.</author><author>Thomas, R.~C.</author><author>Nugent, P.</author><author>Howell, D.~A.</author><author>Gal-Yam, A.</author><author>Arcavi, I.</author><author>Ben-Ami, S.</author><author>Blake, S.</author><author>Botyanszki, J.</author><author>Buton, C.</author><author>Cooke, J.</author><author>Ellis, R.~S.</author><author>Hook, I.~M.</author><author>Kasliwal, M.~M.</author><author>Pan, Y.-C.</author><author>Pereira, R.</author><author>Podsiadlowski, P.</author><author>Sternberg, A.</author><author>Suzuki, N.</author><author>Xu, D.</author><author>Yaron, O.</author><author>Bloom, J.~S.</author><author>Cenko, S.~B.</author><author>Kulkarni, S.~R.</author><author>Law, N.</author><author>Ofek, E.~O.</author><author>Poznanski, D.</author><author>Quimby, R.~M.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>PTF10ops - a subluminous, normal-width light curve Type Ia supernova in the middle of nowhere</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>418</volume><pages>747-758</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates><date>December</date></pub-dates></dates><label>mag11</label><keywords><keyword>supernovae: general, supernovae: individual: PTF10ops</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/maguire2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.19526.x</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1108.0416</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2011MNRAS.418..747M</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.19526.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>PTF10ops is a Type Ia supernova (SN Ia), whose light curve and spectral properties place it outside the current SN Ia subtype classifications. Its spectra display the characteristic lines of subluminous SNe Ia, but it has a normal-width light curve with a long rise time, typical of normal-luminosity SNe Ia. The early-time optical spectra of PTF10ops were modelled using a spectral fitting code and found to have all the lines typically seen in subluminous SNe Ia, without the need to invoke more uncommon elements. The host galaxy environment of PTF10ops is also unusual with no galaxy detected at the position of the SN down to an absolute limiting magnitude of r&gt;=-12.0 mag, but a very massive galaxy is present at a separation of ˜148 kpc and at the same redshift as suggested by the SN spectral features. The progenitor of PTF10ops is most likely a very old star, possibly in a low-metallicity environment, which affects its explosion mechanism and observational characteristics. PTF10ops does not easily fit into any of the current models of either subluminous or normal SN Ia progenitor channels.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>16/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>16/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>404</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Maguire, K.</author><author>Sullivan, M.</author><author>Ellis, R.~S.</author><author>Nugent, P.~E.</author><author>Howell, D.~A.</author><author>Gal-Yam, A.</author><author>Cooke, J.</author><author>Mazzali, P.</author><author>Pan, Y.-C.</author><author>Dilday, B.</author><author>Thomas, R.~C.</author><author>Arcavi, I.</author><author>Ben-Ami, S.</author><author>Bersier, D.</author><author>Bianco, F.~B.</author><author>Fulton, B.~J.</author><author>Hook, I.</author><author>Horesh, A.</author><author>Hsiao, E.</author><author>James, P.~A.</author><author>Podsiadlowski, P.</author><author>Walker, E.~S.</author><author>Yaron, O.</author><author>Kasliwal, M.~M.</author><author>Laher, R.~R.</author><author>Law, N.~M.</author><author>Ofek, E.~O.</author><author>Poznanski, D.</author><author>Surace, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Hubble Space Telescope studies of low-redshift Type Ia supernovae: evolution with redshift and ultraviolet spectral trends</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>426</volume><pages>2359-2379</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>November</date></pub-dates></dates><label>mag12a</label><keywords><keyword>supernovae: general, galaxies: general, distance scale, cosmological parameters</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/maguire2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.21909.x</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1205.7040</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2012MNRAS.426.2359M</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.21909.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present an analysis of the maximum light, near-ultraviolet (NUV; 2900 &lt; lambda &lt; 5500 Å) spectra of 32 low-redshift (0.001 &lt; z &lt; 0.08) Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia), obtained with the Hubble Space Telescope (HST) using the Space Telescope Imaging Spectrograph. We combine this spectroscopic sample with high-quality gri light curves obtained with robotic telescopes to measure SN Ia photometric parameters, such as stretch (light-curve width), optical colour and brightness (Hubble residual). By comparing our new data to a comparable sample of SNe Ia at intermediate redshift (0.4 &lt; z &lt; 0.9), we detect modest spectral evolution (3sigma), in the sense that our mean low-redshift NUV spectrum has a depressed flux compared to its intermediate-redshift counterpart. We also see a strongly increased dispersion about the mean with decreasing wavelength, confirming the results of earlier surveys. We show that these trends are consistent with changes in metallicity as predicted by contemporary SN Ia spectral models. We also examine the properties of various NUV spectral diagnostics in the individual SN spectra. We find a general correlation between SN stretch and the velocity (or position) of many NUV spectral features. In particular, we observe that higher stretch SNe have larger Ca II H&amp;K velocities, which also correlate with host galaxy stellar mass. This latter trend is probably driven by the well-established correlation between stretch and host galaxy stellar mass. We find no significant trends between UV spectral features and optical colour. Mean spectra constructed according to whether the SN has a positive or negative Hubble residual show very little difference at NUV wavelengths, indicating that the NUV evolution and variation we identify does not directly correlate with Hubble diagram residuals. Our work confirms and strengthens earlier conclusions regarding the complex behaviour of SNe Ia in the NUV spectral region, but suggests the correlations we find are more useful in constraining progenitor models rather than improving the use of SNe Ia as cosmological probes.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>16/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>16/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>733</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mankowski, T.</author><author>Slater, S.~J.</author><author>Slater, T.~F.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>An Interpretive Study Of Meanings Citizen Scientists Make When Participating In Galaxy Zoo</title><secondary-title>Contemporary Issues in Education Research</secondary-title></titles><volume>4</volume><number>4</number><pages>25-42</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates><date>April</date></pub-dates></dates><label>man11b</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/mankowski2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>18/01/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>790</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Mosleh, M.</author><author>Romer, A.~K.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Campbell, H.~C.</author><author>Crowcroft, B.</author><author>Doyle, I.</author><author>Edmondson, E.~M.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.~S.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: passive red spirals</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>405</volume><pages>783-799</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>mas10a</label><keywords><keyword>surveys, galaxies: active, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: photometry, galaxies: spiral</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/masters2010.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.16503.x</electronic-resource-num><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>19/09/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>525</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Nichol, R.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Mosleh, M.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Edmondson, E.~M.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.~S.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: dust in spiral galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>404</volume><pages>792-810</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>May</date></pub-dates></dates><label>mas10b</label><keywords><keyword>surveys, dust, extinction, galaxies: fundamental parameters, galaxies: photometry, galaxies: spiral</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/masters2010a.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.16335.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.16335.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We investigate the effect of dust on spiral galaxies by measuring the inclination dependence of optical colours for 24276 well-resolved Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) galaxies visually classified via the Galaxy Zoo project. We find clear trends of reddening with inclination which imply a total extinction from face-on to edge-on of 0.7, 0.6, 0.5 and 0.4mag for the ugri passbands (estimating 0.3mag of extinction in z band). We split the sample into discy&apos; (late-type) spirals using the SDSS fracdeV (or fDeV) parameter and show that the average face-on colour of discy&apos; spirals. This shows that the observed optical colour of a spiral galaxy is determined almost equally by the spiral type (via the bulge-disc ratio and stellar populations), and reddening due to dust. We find that both luminosity and spiral type affect the total amount of extinction, with discy spirals at Mr ~ -21.5mag having the most reddening - more than twice as much as both the lowest luminosity and most massive, bulge-dominated spirals. An increase in dust content is well known for more luminous galaxies, but the decrease of the trend for the most luminous has not been observed before and may be related to their lower levels of recent star formation. We compare our results with the latest dust attenuation models of Tuffs et al. We find that the model reproduces the observed trends reasonably well but overpredicts the amount of u-band attenuation in edge-on galaxies. This could be an inadequacy in the Milky Way extinction law (when applied to external galaxies), but more likely indicates the need for a wider range of dust-star geometries. We end by discussing the effects of dust on large galaxy surveys and emphasize that these effects will become important as we push to higher precision measurements of galaxy properties and their clustering.  This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 160000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/Volunteers.aspx  E-mail: karen.masters@port.ac.uk</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>692</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Hoyle, B.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Edmondson, E.~M.</author><author>Fortson, L.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Smith, A.~M.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: bars in disc galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>411</volume><pages>2026-2034</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates><date>March</date></pub-dates></dates><label>mas11c</label><keywords><keyword>surveys, galaxies: bulges, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: photometry, galaxies: spiral, galaxies: structure</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/masters2011a.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.17834.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.17834.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present first results from Galaxy Zoo 2, the second phase of the highly successful Galaxy Zoo project (). Using a volume-limited sample of 13 665 disc galaxies (0.01 &lt; z &lt; 0.06 and Mr &lt; -19.38), we study the fraction of galaxies with bars as a function of global galaxy properties like colour, luminosity and bulge prominence. Overall, 29.4 $\pm$ 0.5 per cent of galaxies in our sample have a bar, in excellent agreement with previous visually classified samples of galaxies (although this overall fraction is lower than that measured by automated bar-finding methods). We see a clear increase in the bar fraction with redder (g-r) colours, decreased luminosity and in galaxies with more prominent bulges, to the extent that over half of the red, bulge-dominated disc galaxies in our sample possess a bar. We see evidence for a colour bimodality for our sample of disc galaxies, with a &apos;red sequence&apos; that is both bulge and bar dominated, and a &apos;blue cloud&apos; which has little, or no, evidence for a (classical) bulge or bar. These results are consistent with similar trends for barred galaxies seen recently both locally and at higher redshift, and with early studies using the RC3. We discuss these results in the context of internal (secular) galaxy evolution scenarios and the possible links to the formation of bars and bulges in disc galaxies. This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 200 000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/Volunteers.aspx</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>12/04/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>582</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Haynes, M.~P.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Simmons, B.</author><author>Skibba, R.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Giovanelli, R.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo and ALFALFA: atomic gas and the regulation of star formation in barred disc galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>424</volume><pages>2180-2192</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>August</date></pub-dates></dates><label>mas12a</label><keywords><keyword>surveys, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: ISM, galaxies: spiral, galaxies: statistics, galaxies: structure</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/masters2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.21377.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.21377.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We study the observed correlation between atomic gas content and the likelihood of hosting a large-scale bar in a sample of 2090 disc galaxies. Such a test has never been done before on this scale. We use data on morphologies from the Galaxy Zoo project and information on the galaxies&apos; H I content from the Arecibo Legacy Fast Arecibo L-band Feed Array (ALFALFA) blind H I survey. Our main result is that the bar fraction is significantly lower among gas-rich disc galaxies than gas-poor ones. This is not explained by known trends for more massive (stellar) and redder disc galaxies to host more bars and have lower gas fractions: we still see at fixed stellar mass a residual correlation between gas content and bar fraction. We discuss three possible causal explanations: (1) bars in disc galaxies cause atomic gas to be used up more quickly, (2) increasing the atomic gas content in a disc galaxy inhibits bar formation and (3) bar fraction and gas content are both driven by correlation with environmental effects (e.g. tidal triggering of bars, combined with strangulation removing gas). All three explanations are consistent with the observed correlations. In addition our observations suggest bars may reduce or halt star formation in the outer parts of discs by holding back the infall of external gas beyond bar co-rotation, reddening the global colours of barred disc galaxies. This suggests that secular evolution driven by the exchange of angular momentum between stars in the bar, and gas in the disc, acts as a feedback mechanism to regulate star formation in intermediate-mass disc galaxies. This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 200 000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at South East Physics Network, E-mail: karen.masters@port.ac.ukEinstein fellow.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>12/10/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>474</rec-number><ref-type>47</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Masters, K.~L.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>A Zoo of Galaxies</title><secondary-title>XXVIIIth IAU General Assembly</secondary-title></titles><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>August</date></pub-dates></dates><label>mas13</label><keywords><keyword>Astrophysics - Cosmology and Extragalactic Astrophysics</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/masters2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><abstract>We live in a universe filled with galaxies with an amazing variety of sizes and shapes. One of the biggest challenges for astronomers working in this field is to understand how all these types relate to each other in the background of an expanding universe. Modern astronomical surveys (like the Sloan Digital Sky Survey) have revolutionised this field of astronomy, by providing vast numbers of galaxies to study. The sheer size of the these databases made traditional visual classification of the types galaxies impossible and in 2007 inspired the Galaxy Zoo project (www.galaxyzoo.org); starting the largest ever scientific collaboration by asking members of the public to help classify galaxies by type and shape. Galaxy Zoo has since shown itself, in a series of now more than 30 scientific papers, to be a fantastic database for the study of galaxy evolution. In this Invited Discourse I spoke a little about the historical background of our understanding of what galaxies are, of galaxy classification, about our modern view of galaxies in the era of large surveys. I finish with showcasing some of the contributions galaxy classifications from the Galaxy Zoo project are making to our understanding of galaxy evolution. This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 200,000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/volunteers. KLM acknowledges funding from the Peter and Patricia Gruber Foundation as the 2008 Peter and Patricia Gruber Foundation IAU Fellow, and from a 2010 Leverhulme Trust Early Career Fellowship, as well as support from the Royal Astronomical Society to attend the 28th GA of the IAU.</abstract><custom3>inproceedings</custom3><added-date>29/03/2013</added-date><modified-date>22/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>406</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Parker, A.~H.</author><author>Buie, M.~W.</author><author>Osip, D.~J.</author><author>Gwyn, S.~D.~J.</author><author>Holman, M.~J.</author><author>Borncamp, D.~M.</author><author>Spencer, J.~R.</author><author>Benecchi, S.~D.</author><author>Binzel, R.~P.</author><author>DeMeo, F.~E.</author><author>Fabbro, S.</author><author>Fuentes, C.~I.</author><author>Gay, P.~L.</author><author>Kavelaars, J.~J.</author><author>McLeod, B.~A.</author><author>Petit, J.-M.</author><author>Sheppard, S.~S.</author><author>Stern, S.~A.</author><author>Tholen, D.~J.</author><author>Trilling, D.~E.</author><author>Ragozzine, D.~A.</author><author>Wasserman, L.~H.</author><author>Ice Hunters, t.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>2011 HM$_102$: Discovery of a High-inclination L5 Neptune Trojan in the Search for a Post-Pluto New Horizons Target</title><secondary-title>\aj</secondary-title></titles><volume>145</volume><pages>96</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>April</date></pub-dates></dates><label>par13</label><keywords><keyword>minor planets, asteroids: general</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/parker2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0004-6256/145/4/96</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1210.4549</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013AJ....145...96P</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0004-6256/145/4/96</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present the discovery of a long-term stable L5 (trailing) Neptune Trojan in data acquired to search for candidate trans-Neptunian objects for the New Horizons spacecraft to fly by during an extended post-Pluto mission. This Neptune Trojan, 2011 HM102, has the highest inclination (29.$\,^\circ$4) of any known member of this population. It is intrinsically brighter than any single L5 Jupiter Trojan at HV ~ 8.18. We have determined its gri colors (a first for any L5 Neptune Trojan), which we find to be similar to the moderately red colors of the L4 Neptune Trojans, suggesting similar surface properties for members of both Trojan clouds. We also present colors derived from archival data for two L4 Neptune Trojans (2006 RJ103 and 2007 VL305), better refining the overall color distribution of the population. In this document we describe the discovery circumstances, our physical characterization of 2011 HM102, and this object&apos;s implications for the Neptune Trojan population overall. Finally, we discuss the prospects for detecting 2011 HM102 from the New Horizons spacecraft during its close approach in mid- to late-2013.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>16/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>16/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>696</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Bracey, G.</author><author>Gay, P.~L.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Szalay, A.~S.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: Exploring the Motivations of Citizen Science Volunteers</title><secondary-title>Astronomy Education Review</secondary-title></titles><volume>9</volume><number>1</number><pages>010103</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates></pub-dates></dates><label>rad10</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/raddick2010a.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.3847/AER2009036</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The Galaxy Zoo citizen science website invites anyone with an Internet connection to participate in research by classifying galaxies from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. As of April 2009, more than 200,000 volunteers had made more than 100 million galaxy classifications. In this paper, we present results of a pilot study into the motivations and demographics of Galaxy Zoo volunteers, and define a technique to determine motivations from free responses that can be used in larger multiple-choice surveys with similar populations. Our categories form the basis for a future survey, with the goal of determining the prevalence of each motivation.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/03/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>476</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Bracey, G.</author><author>Gay, P.~L.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Cardamone, C.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Szalay, A.~S.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: Motivations of Citizen Scientists</title><secondary-title>ArXiv e-prints</secondary-title></titles><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>March</date></pub-dates></dates><label>rad13</label><keywords><keyword>Physics - Physics Education, Astrophysics - Cosmology and Extragalactic Astrophysics</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/raddick2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><abstract>Citizen science, in which volunteers work with professional scientists to conduct research, is expanding due to large online datasets. To plan projects, it is important to understand volunteers&apos; motivations for participating. This paper analyzes results from an online survey of nearly 11,000 volunteers in Galaxy Zoo, an astronomy citizen science project. Results show that volunteers&apos; primary motivation is a desire to contribute to scientific research. We encourage other citizen science projects to study the motivations of their volunteers, to see whether and how these results may be generalized to inform the field of citizen science.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>28/03/2013</added-date><modified-date>28/03/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>405</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Savani, N.~P.</author><author>Davies, J.~A.</author><author>Davis, C.~J.</author><author>Shiota, D.</author><author>Rouillard, A.~P.</author><author>Owens, M.~J.</author><author>Kusano, K.</author><author>Bothmer, V.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Smith, A.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Observational Tracking of the 2D Structure of Coronal Mass Ejections Between the Sun and 1 AU</title><secondary-title>\solphys</secondary-title></titles><volume>279</volume><pages>517-535</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>August</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sav12</label><keywords><keyword>Coronal mass ejections (CMEs), Heliosphere, Solar-terrestrial relations, Solar wind</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11207-012-0041-6</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2012SoPh..279..517S</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s11207-012-0041-6</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The Solar TErrestrial RElations Observatory (STEREO) provides high cadence and high resolution images of the structure and morphology of coronal mass ejections (CMEs) in the inner heliosphere. CME directions and propagation speeds have often been estimated through the use of time-elongation maps obtained from the STEREO Heliospheric Imager (HI) data. Many of these CMEs have been identified by citizen scientists working within the SolarStormWatch project (&lt;ExternalRef&gt; &lt;RefSource&gt; www.solarstormwatch.com &lt;/RefSource&gt; &lt;RefTarget Address=&quot;http://www.solarstormwatch.com&quot; TargetType=&quot;URL&quot;/&gt; &lt;/ExternalRef&gt;) as they work towards providing robust real-time identification of Earth-directed CMEs. The wide field of view of HI allows scientists to directly observe the two-dimensional (2D) structures, while the relative simplicity of time-elongation analysis means that it can be easily applied to many such events, thereby enabling a much deeper understanding of how CMEs evolve between the Sun and the Earth. For events with certain orientations, both the rear and front edges of the CME can be monitored at varying heliocentric distances ( R) between the Sun and 1 AU. Here we take four example events with measurable position angle widths and identified by the citizen scientists. These events were chosen for the clarity of their structure within the HI cameras and their long track lengths in the time-elongation maps. We show a linear dependency with R for the growth of the radial width ( W) and the 2D aspect ratio ( chi) of these CMEs, which are measured out to ≈ 0.7 AU. We estimated the radial width from a linear best fit for the average of the four CMEs. We obtained the relationships W=0.14 R+0.04 for the width and chi=2.5 R+0.86 for the aspect ratio ( W and R in units of AU).</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>16/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>16/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>407</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sayigh, Laela</author><author>Quick, Nicola</author><author>Hastie, Gordon</author><author>Tyack, Peter</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Repeated call types in short-finned pilot whales, Globicephala macrorhynchus</title><secondary-title>Marine Mammal Science</secondary-title></titles><volume>29</volume><number>2</number><pages>312--324</pages><publisher>Blackwell Publishing Inc</publisher><isbn>1748-7692</isbn><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates></pub-dates></dates><label>say13</label><keywords><keyword>pilot whale, Globicephala macrorhynchus, repeated calls, spectrograms, vocal behavior</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/sayigh2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1748-7692.2012.00577.x</electronic-resource-num><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>16/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>16/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>888</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Sarzi, M.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Khochfar, S.</author><author>Land, K.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author><author>Yi, S.~K.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: a sample of blue early-type galaxies at low redshift</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>396</volume><pages>818-829</pages><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sch09</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, cD , galaxies: evolution , galaxies: formation , galaxies: fundamental parameters , galaxies: starburst</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/schawinski2009.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2009.14793.x</electronic-resource-num><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>19/04/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>715</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Urry, C.~M.</author><author>Virani, S.</author><author>Coppi, P.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Treister, E.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Sarzi, M.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Cardamone, C.~N.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Ross, N.~P.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.~S.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: The Fundamentally Different Co-Evolution of Supermassive Black Holes and Their Early- and Late-Type Host Galaxies</title><secondary-title>\apj</secondary-title></titles><volume>711</volume><pages>284-302</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>March</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sch10a</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: active, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: formation, galaxies: Seyfert</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/schawinski2010b.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0004-637X/711/1/284</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0004-637X/711/1/284</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We use data from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and visual classifications of morphology from the Galaxy Zoo project to study black hole growth in the nearby universe (z &lt; 0.05) and to break down the active galactic nucleus (AGN) host galaxy population by color, stellar mass, and morphology. We find that the black hole growth at luminosities L[O III] &gt;1040 erg s-1 in early- and late-type galaxies is fundamentally different. AGN host galaxies as a population have a broad range of stellar masses (1010-1011 M sun), reside in the green valley of the color-mass diagram and their central black holes have median masses around 106.5 M sun. However, by comparing early- and late-type AGN host galaxies to their non-active counterparts, we find several key differences: in early-type galaxies, it is preferentially the galaxies with the least massive black holes that are growing, while in late-type galaxies, it is preferentially the most massive black holes that are growing. The duty cycle of AGNs in early-type galaxies is strongly peaked in the green valley below the low-mass end (1010 M sun) of the red sequence at stellar masses where there is a steady supply of blue cloud progenitors. The duty cycle of AGNs in late-type galaxies on the other hand peaks in massive (1011 M sun) green and red late-types which generally do not have a corresponding blue cloud population of similar mass. At high-Eddington ratios (L/L Edd&gt;0.1), the only population with a substantial fraction of AGNs are the low-mass green valley early-type galaxies. Finally, the Milky Way likely resides in the &quot;sweet spot&quot; on the color-mass diagram where the AGN duty cycle of late-type galaxies is highest. We discuss the implications of these results for our understanding of the role of AGNs in the evolution of galaxies.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/02/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>19</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Schmitt, Joseph~R.</author><author>Wang, Ji</author><author>Fischer, Debra~A.</author><author>Jek, Kian~J.</author><author>Moriarty, John~C.</author><author>Boyajian, Tabetha~S.</author><author>Schwamb, Megan~E.</author><author>Lintott, Chris</author><author>Smith, Arfon~M.</author><author>Parrish, Michael</author><author>Schawinski, Kevin</author><author>Lynn, Stuart</author><author>Simpson, Robert</author><author>Omohundro, Mark</author><author>Winarski, Troy</author><author>Goodman, Samuel~J.</author><author>Jebson, Tony</author><author>Lacourse, Daryll</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Planet Hunters VI: The First Kepler Seven Planet Candidate System and 13 Other Planet Candidates from the Kepler Archival Data</title></titles><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>Oct</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sch13a</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/schmitt2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://arxiv.org/abs/1310.5912v1</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/bib_query?arXiv:1310.5912</url></related-urls></urls><abstract>We report the discovery of 14 new transiting planet candidates in the Kepler field from the Planet Hunters citizen science program. None of these candidates overlap with Kepler Objects of Interest (KOIs), and five of the candidates were missed by the Kepler Transit Planet Search (TPS) algorithm. The new candidates have periods ranging from 124-904 days, eight residing in their host star&apos;s habitable zone (HZ) and two (now) in multiple planet systems. We report the discovery of one more addition to the six planet candidate system around KOI-351, marking the first seven planet candidate system from Kepler. Additionally, KOI-351 bears some resemblance to our own solar system, with the inner five planets ranging from Earth to mini-Neptune radii and the outer planets being gas giants; however, this system is very compact, with all seven planet candidates orbiting $\lesssim 1$ AU from their host star. We perform a numerical integration of the orbits and show that the system remains stable for over 100 million years. A Hill stability test also confirms the feasibility for the dynamical stability of the KOI-351 system.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>22/10/2013</added-date><modified-date>22/10/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>584</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Schwamb, M.~E.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Fischer, D.~A.</author><author>Giguere, M.~J.</author><author>Lynn, S.</author><author>Smith, A.~M.</author><author>Brewer, J.~M.</author><author>Parrish, M.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Simpson, R.~J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Planet Hunters: Assessing the Kepler Inventory of Short-period Planets</title><secondary-title>\apj</secondary-title></titles><volume>754</volume><pages>129</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>August</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sch12</label><keywords><keyword>planets and satellites: detection, planets and satellites: general</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/schwamb2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0004-637X/754/2/129</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present the results from a search of data from the first 33.5 days of the Kepler science mission (Quarter 1) for exoplanet transits by the Planet Hunters citizen science project. Planet Hunters enlists members of the general public to visually identify transits in the publicly released Kepler light curves via the World Wide Web. Over 24,000 volunteers reviewed the Kepler Quarter 1 data set. We examine the abundance of &gt;=2 R ⊕ planets on short-period (&lt;15 days) orbits based on Planet Hunters detections. We present these results along with an analysis of the detection efficiency of human classifiers to identify planetary transits including a comparison to the Kepler inventory of planet candidates. Although performance drops rapidly for smaller radii, &gt;=4 R ⊕ Planet Hunters &gt;=85% efficient at identifying transit signals for planets with periods less than 15 days for the Kepler sample of target stars. Our high efficiency rate for simulated transits along with recovery of the majority of Kepler &gt;=4 R ⊕ planets suggests that the Kepler inventory of &gt;=4 R ⊕ short-period planets is nearly complete.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>12/10/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>391</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Schwamb, M.~E.</author><author>Orosz, J.~A.</author><author>Carter, J.~A.</author><author>Welsh, W.~F.</author><author>Fischer, D.~A.</author><author>Torres, G.</author><author>Howard, A.~W.</author><author>Crepp, J.~R.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Kaib, N.~A.</author><author>Terrell, D.</author><author>Gagliano, R.</author><author>Jek, K.~J.</author><author>Parrish, M.</author><author>Smith, A.~M.</author><author>Lynn, S.</author><author>Simpson, R.~J.</author><author>Giguere, M.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Planet Hunters: A Transiting Circumbinary Planet in a Quadruple Star System</title><secondary-title>\apj</secondary-title></titles><volume>768</volume><pages>127</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>May</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sch13</label><keywords><keyword>binaries: eclipsing, planets and satellites: detection, planets and satellites: general, stars: individual: KIC 4862625</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/schwamb2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0004-637X/768/2/127</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1210.3612</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013ApJ...768..127S</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0004-637X/768/2/127</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We report the discovery and confirmation of a transiting circumbinary planet (PH1b) around KIC 4862625, an eclipsing binary in the Kepler field. The planet was discovered by volunteers searching the first six Quarters of publicly available Kepler data as part of the Planet Hunters citizen science project. Transits of the planet across the larger and brighter of the eclipsing stars are detectable by visual inspection every ~137 days, with seven transits identified in Quarters 1-11. The physical and orbital parameters of both the host stars and planet were obtained via a photometric-dynamical model, simultaneously fitting both the measured radial velocities and the Kepler light curve of KIC 4862625. The 6.18 $\pm$ 0.17 R ⊕ planet orbits outside the 20 day orbit of an eclipsing binary consisting of an F dwarf (1.734 $\pm$ 0.044 R &amp;sun;, 1.528 $\pm$ 0.087 M &amp;sun;) and M dwarf (0.378 $\pm$ 0.023 R &amp;sun;, 0.408 $\pm$ 0.024 M &amp;sun;). For the planet, we find an upper mass limit of 169 M ⊕ (0.531 Jupiter masses) at the 99.7% confidence level. With a radius and mass less than that of Jupiter, PH1b is well within the planetary regime. Outside the planet&apos;s orbit, at ~1000 AU, a previously unknown visual binary has been identified that is likely bound to the planetary system, making this the first known case of a quadruple star system with a transiting planet.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>22/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>22/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>393</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Shabala, S.~S.</author><author>Ting, Y.-S.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Crockett, R.~M.</author><author>Silk, J.</author><author>Sarzi, M.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Edmondson, E.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: dust lane early-type galaxies are tracers of recent, gas-rich minor mergers</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>423</volume><pages>59-67</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sha12b</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: active, galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, cD, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: interactions</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/shabala2012b.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.20598.x</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1107.5310</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2012MNRAS.423...59S</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.20598.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present the second of two papers concerning the origin and evolution of local early-type galaxies exhibiting dust features. We use optical and radio data to examine the nature of active galactic nucleus (AGN) activity in these objects, and compare these with a carefully constructed control sample.  We find that dust lane early-type galaxies are much more likely to host emission-line AGN than the control sample galaxies. Moreover, there is a strong correlation between radio and emission-line AGN activity in dust lane early types, but not the control sample. Dust lane early-type galaxies show the same distribution of AGN properties in rich and poor environments, suggesting a similar triggering mechanism. By contrast, this is not the case for early types with no dust features. These findings strongly suggest that dust lane early-type galaxies are starburst systems formed in gas-rich mergers. Further evidence in support of this scenario is provided by enhanced star formation and black hole accretion rates in these objects. Dust lane early types therefore represent an evolutionary stage between starbursting and quiescent galaxies. In these objects, the AGN has already been triggered but has not as yet completely destroyed the gas reservoir required for star formation. This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 250 000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo 2 project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at .</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>22/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>22/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>496</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Simmons, B.~D.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Moran, E.~C.</author><author>Han, A.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Urry, C.~M.</author><author>Willett, K.~W.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: bulgeless galaxies with growing black holes</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>429</volume><pages>2199-2211</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>March</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sim13</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: active, galaxies: bulges, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: general, galaxies: Seyfert, galaxies: spiral</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/simmons2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/mnras/sts491</electronic-resource-num><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>21/02/2013</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>642</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Simpson, E.</author><author>Roberts, S.</author><author>Psorakis, I.</author><author>Smith, A.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Dynamic Bayesian Combination of Multiple Imperfect Classifiers</title><secondary-title>ArXiv e-prints</secondary-title></titles><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sim12</label><keywords><keyword>Mathematics - Statistics Theory, Astrophysics - Instrumentation and Methods for Astrophysics</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/simpson2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><abstract>Classifier combination methods need to make best use of the outputs of multiple, imperfect classifiers to enable higher accuracy classifications. In many situations, such as when human decisions need to be combined, the base decisions can vary enormously in reliability. A Bayesian approach to such uncertain combination allows us to infer the differences in performance between individuals and to incorporate any available prior knowledge about their abilities when training data is sparse. In this paper we explore Bayesian classifier combination, using the computationally efficient framework of variational Bayesian inference. We apply the approach to real data from a large citizen science project, Galaxy Zoo Supernovae, and show that our method far outperforms other established approaches to imperfect decision combination. We go on to analyse the putative community structure of the decision makers, based on their inferred decision making strategies, and show that natural groupings are formed. Finally we present a dynamic Bayesian classifier combination approach and investigate the changes in base classifier performance over time.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>17/07/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>527</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Simpson, R.~J.</author><author>Povich, M.~S.</author><author>Kendrew, S.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Bressert, E.</author><author>Arvidsson, K.</author><author>Cyganowski, C.</author><author>Maddison, S.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Sherman, R.</author><author>Smith, A.~M.</author><author>Wolf-Chase, G.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>The Milky Way Project First Data Release: a bubblier Galactic disc</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>424</volume><pages>2442-2460</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>August</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sim12a</label><keywords><keyword>stars: formation, dust, extinction, H II regions, infrared: ISM</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/simpson2012a.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.20770.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.20770.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present a new catalogue of 5106 infrared bubbles created through visual classification via the online citizen science website &apos;The Milky Way Project&apos;. Bubbles in the new catalogue have been independently measured by at least five individuals, producing consensus parameters for their position, radius, thickness, eccentricity and position angle. Citizen scientists - volunteers recruited online and taking part in this research - have independently rediscovered the locations of at least 86 per cent of three widely used catalogues of bubbles and H II regions whilst finding an order of magnitude more objects. 29 per cent of the Milky Way Project catalogue bubbles lie on the rim of a larger bubble, or have smaller bubbles located within them, opening up the possibility of better statistical studies of triggered star formation. Also outlined is the creation of a &apos;heat map&apos; of star formation activity in the Galactic plane. This online resource provides a crowd-sourced map of bubbles and arcs in the Milky Way, and will enable better statistical analysis of Galactic star formation sites.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>802</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Skibba, R.~A.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Edmondson, E.~M.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Szalay, A.~S.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: disentangling the environmental dependence of morphology and colour</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>399</volume><pages>966-982</pages><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>October</date></pub-dates></dates><label>ski09</label><keywords><keyword>methods: statistical , galaxies: clusters: general , galaxies: evolution , galaxies: haloes , galaxies: structure , large-scale structure of Universe</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/skibba2009a.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2009.15334.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We analyse the environmental dependence of galaxy morphology and colour with two-point clustering statistics, using data from the Galaxy Zoo, the largest sample of visually classified morphologies yet compiled, extracted from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. We present two-point correlation functions of spiral and early-type galaxies, and we quantify the correlation between morphology and environment with marked correlation functions. These yield clear and precise environmental trends across a wide range of scales, analogous to similar measurements with galaxy colours, indicating that the Galaxy Zoo classifications themselves are very precise. We measure morphology marked correlation functions at fixed colour and find that they are relatively weak, with the only residual correlation being that of red galaxies at small scales, indicating a morphology gradient within haloes for red galaxies. At fixed morphology, we find that the environmental dependence of colour remains strong, and these correlations remain for fixed morphology and luminosity. An implication of this is that much of the morphology-density relation is due to the relation between colour and density. Our results also have implications for galaxy evolution: the morphological transformation of galaxies is usually accompanied by a colour transformation, but not necessarily vice versa. A spiral galaxy may move on to the red sequence of the colour-magnitude diagram without quickly becoming an early type. We analyse the significant population of red spiral galaxies, and present evidence that they tend to be located in moderately dense environments and are often satellite galaxies in the outskirts of haloes. Finally, we combine our results to argue that central and satellite galaxies tend to follow different evolutionary paths.  This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 100000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/Volunteers.aspx  E-mail: skibba@mpia.de</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>08/08/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>544</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Skibba, R.~A.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Zehavi, I.</author><author>Hoyle, B.</author><author>Edmondson, E.~M.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Cardamone, C.~N.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: the environmental dependence of bars and bulges in disc galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>423</volume><pages>1485-1502</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>ski12</label><keywords><keyword>methods: statistical, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: haloes, galaxies: spiral, galaxies: structure, large-scale structure of the Universe</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/skibba2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.20972.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.20972.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present an analysis of the environmental dependence of bars and bulges in disc galaxies, using a volume-limited catalogue of 15 810 galaxies at z &lt; 0.06 from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey with visual morphologies from the Galaxy Zoo 2 project. We find that the likelihood of having a bar, or bulge, in disc galaxies increases when the galaxies have redder (optical) colours and larger stellar masses, and observe a transition in the bar and bulge likelihoods at M*= 2 × 1010 M&amp;sun;, such that massive disc galaxies are more likely to host bars and bulges. In addition, while some barred and most bulge-dominated galaxies are on the `red sequence&apos; of the colour-magnitude diagram, we see a wider variety of colours for galaxies that host bars. We use galaxy clustering methods to demonstrate statistically significant environmental correlations of barred, and bulge-dominated, galaxies, from projected separations of 150 kpc h-1 to 3 Mpc h-1. These environmental correlations appear to be independent of each other: i.e. bulge-dominated disc galaxies exhibit a significant bar-environment correlation, and barred disc galaxies show a bulge-environment correlation. As a result of sparse sampling tests - our sample is nearly 20 times larger than those used previously - we argue that previous studies that did not detect a bar-environment correlation were likely inhibited by small number statistics. We demonstrate that approximately half of the bar-environment correlation can be explained by the fact that more massive dark matter haloes host redder disc galaxies, which are then more likely to have bars; this fraction is estimated to be 50 $\pm$ 10 per cent from a mock catalogue analysis and 60 $\pm$ 5 per cent from the data. Likewise, we show that the environmental dependence of stellar mass can only explain a smaller fraction (25 $\pm$ 10 per cent) of the bar-environment correlation. Therefore, a significant fraction of our observed environmental dependence of barred galaxies is not due to colour or stellar mass dependences, and hence must be due to another galaxy property, such as gas content, or to environmental influences. Finally, by analysing the projected clustering of barred and unbarred disc galaxies with halo occupation models, we argue that barred galaxies are in slightly higher mass haloes than unbarred ones, and some of them (approximately 25 per cent) are satellite galaxies in groups. We discuss the implications of our results on the effects of minor mergers and interactions on bar formation in disc galaxies.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>12/10/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>709</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Slater, S.~J.</author><author>Slater, T.~F.</author><author>Lyons, D.~J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Teaching Scientific Inquiry with Galaxy Zoo</title><secondary-title>The Physics Teacher</secondary-title></titles><volume>49</volume><pages>94-96</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates><date>February</date></pub-dates></dates><label>sla11</label><keywords><keyword>astronomy, Galaxy, physics education, teaching, Educational aids, Education, Characteristics and properties of the Milky Way galaxy</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/slater2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1119/1.3543583</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The universe of topics to choose from when teaching an astronomy course is astronomically immense. This wide array of opportunity presents some inherently difficult choices for teachers at all levels on how to limit the scope of the course to make the syllabus manageable. As but one example, consider that even the most experienced astronomy teacher must choose between focusing on the astrophysics of stellar processes or on the nomenclature for stars and constellations because there is rarely time to give both justice. One might go as far as saying that planning an astronomy course is similar to the perspective offered by Michael Pollan in his book The Omnivore&apos;s Dilemma, which can be paraphrased as, ``When entering a modern grocery store in the U.S. with unlimited choices, what is it that one chooses to eat and why?&apos;&apos; Indeed, teaching about the entire universe in a single astronomy course involves some serious choices, as one can most certainly not teach everything.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>07/03/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>673</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Slosar, A.</author><author>Land, K.</author><author>Bamford, S.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Nichol, R.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: chiral correlation function of galaxy spins</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>392</volume><pages>1225-1232</pages><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>January</date></pub-dates></dates><label>slo09</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: general , dark matter , large-scale structure of Universe</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/slosar2009.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2008.14127.x</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2008.14127.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Galaxy Zoo is the first study of nearby galaxies that contains reliable information about the spiral sense of rotation of galaxy arms for a sizeable number of galaxies. We measure the correlation function of spin chirality (the sense in which galaxies appear to be spinning) of face-on spiral galaxies in angular, real and projected spaces. Our results indicate a hint of positive correlation at separations less than ~0.5 Mpc at a statistical significance of 2sigma-3sigma. This is the first experimental evidence for chiral correlation of spins. Within the tidal torque theory, it indicates that the inertia tensors of nearby galaxies are correlated. This is complementary to the studies of nearby spin axis correlations that probe the correlations of the tidal field. Theoretical interpretation is made difficult by the small distances at which the correlations are detected, implying that substructure might play a significant role, and our necessary selection of face-on spiral galaxies, rather than a general volume-limited sample.  This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 100000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their individual contributions are acknowledged at http://www.galaxyzoo.org/Volunteers.aspx.  E-mail: anze@berkeley.edu</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>19/05/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>803</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Smith, A.~M.</author><author>Lynn, S.</author><author>Sullivan, M.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Nugent, P.~E.</author><author>Botyanszki, J.</author><author>Kasliwal, M.</author><author>Quimby, R.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Fortson, L.~F.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Hook, I.</author><author>Blake, S.</author><author>Podsiadlowski, P.</author><author>Jönsson, J.</author><author>Gal-Yam, A.</author><author>Arcavi, I.</author><author>Howell, D.~A.</author><author>Bloom, J.~S.</author><author>Jacobsen, J.</author><author>Kulkarni, S.~R.</author><author>Law, N.~M.</author><author>Ofek, E.~O.</author><author>Walters, R.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo Supernovae</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>412</volume><pages>1309-1319</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates><date>April</date></pub-dates></dates><label>smi11</label><keywords><keyword>methods: data analysis, surveys, supernovae: general</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/smith2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.17994.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents the first results from a new citizen science project: Galaxy Zoo Supernovae. This proof-of-concept project uses members of the public to identify supernova candidates from the latest generation of wide-field imaging transient surveys. We describe the Galaxy Zoo Supernovae operations and scoring model, and demonstrate the effectiveness of this novel method using imaging data and transients from the Palomar Transient Factory (PTF). We examine the results collected over the period 2010 April-July, during which nearly 14 000 supernova candidates from the PTF were classified by more than 2500 individuals within a few hours of data collection. We compare the transients selected by the citizen scientists to those identified by experienced PTF scanners and find the agreement to be remarkable - Galaxy Zoo Supernovae performs comparably to the PTF scanners and identified as transients 93 per cent of the ˜130 spectroscopically confirmed supernovae (SNe) that the PTF located during the trial period (with no false positive identifications). Further analysis shows that only a small fraction of the lowest signal-to-noise ratio detections (r &gt; 19.5) are given low scores: Galaxy Zoo Supernovae correctly identifies all SNe with &gt;=8sigma detections in the PTF imaging data. The Galaxy Zoo Supernovae project has direct applicability to future transient searches, such as the Large Synoptic Survey Telescope, by both rapidly identifying candidate transient events and via the training and improvement of existing machine classifier algorithms. This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 10 000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo Supernovae project ().</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>01/08/2011</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>590</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Teng, S.~H.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Urry, C.~M.</author><author>Darg, D.~W.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Oh, K.</author><author>Bonning, E.~W.</author><author>Cardamone, C.~N.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Simmons, B.~D.</author><author>Treister, E.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Chandra Observations of Galaxy Zoo Mergers: Frequency of Binary Active Nuclei in Massive Mergers</title><secondary-title>\apj</secondary-title></titles><volume>753</volume><pages>165</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>July</date></pub-dates></dates><label>ten12</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: active, X-rays: galaxies</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/teng2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0004-637X/753/2/165</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0004-637X/753/2/165</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present the results from a Chandra pilot study of 12 massive galaxy mergers selected from Galaxy Zoo. The sample includes major mergers down to a host galaxy mass of 1011 M &amp;sun; that already have optical active galactic nucleus (AGN) signatures in at least one of the progenitors. We find that the coincidences of optically selected active nuclei with mildly obscured (N H &lt;~ 1.1 × 1022 cm-2) X-ray nuclei are relatively common (8/12), but the detections are too faint (&lt;40 counts per nucleus; f 2-10 keV &lt;~ 1.2 × 10-13 erg s-1 cm-2) to reliably separate starburst and nuclear activity as the origin of the X-ray emission. Only one merger is found to have confirmed binary X-ray nuclei, though the X-ray emission from its southern nucleus could be due solely to star formation. Thus, the occurrences of binary AGNs in these mergers are rare (0%-8%), unless most merger-induced active nuclei are very heavily obscured or Compton thick.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>12/10/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>392</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Tojeiro, R.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Richards, J.</author><author>Percival, W.~J.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Maraston, C.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Skibba, R.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>The different star formation histories of blue and red spiral and elliptical galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>432</volume><pages>359-373</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>toj13</label><keywords><keyword>surveys, galaxies: evolution, galaxies: statistics, galaxies: stellar content</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/tojeiro2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stt484</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1303.3551</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013MNRAS.432..359T</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/mnras/stt484</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We study the spectral properties of intermediate mass galaxies (M* ˜ 1010.7 M&amp;sun;) as a function of colour and morphology. We use Galaxy Zoo to define three morphological classes of galaxies, namely early types (ellipticals), late-type (disc-dominated) face-on spirals and early-type (bulge-dominated) face-on spirals. We classify these galaxies as blue or red according to their Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) g - r colour and use the spectral fitting code Versatile Spectral Analyses to calculate time-resolved star formation histories, metallicity and total starlight dust extinction from their SDSS fibre spectra.  We find that red late-type spirals show less star formation in the last 500 Myr than blue late-type spirals by up to a factor of 3, but share similar star formation histories at earlier times. This decline in recent star formation explains their redder colour: their chemical and dust content are the same. We postulate that red late-type spirals are recent descendants of blue late-type spirals, with their star formation curtailed in the last 500 Myr. The red late-type spirals are however still forming stars ~=17 times faster than red ellipticals over the same period.  Red early-type spirals lie between red late-type spirals and red ellipticals in terms of recent-to-intermediate star formation and dust content. Therefore, it is plausible that these galaxies represent an evolutionary link between these two populations. They are more likely to evolve directly into red ellipticals than red late-type spirals, which show star formation histories and dust content closer to blue late-type spirals.  Blue ellipticals show similar star formation histories as blue spirals (regardless of type), except that they have formed less stars in the last 100 Myr. However, blue ellipticals have different dust content, which peaks at lower extinction values than all spiral galaxies. Therefore, many blue ellipticals are unlikely to be descendants of blue spirals, suggesting there may not be single evolutionary path for this group of galaxies.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>22/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>22/08/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>228</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, J.</author><author>Fischer, D.~A.</author><author>Barclay, T.</author><author>Boyajian, T.~S.</author><author>Crepp, J.~R.</author><author>Schwamb, M.~E.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Jek, K.~J.</author><author>Smith, A.~M.</author><author>Parrish, M.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Schmitt, J.~R.</author><author>Giguere, M.~J.</author><author>Brewer, J.~M.</author><author>Lynn, S.</author><author>Simpson, R.</author><author>Hoekstra, A.~J.</author><author>Jacobs, T.~L.</author><author>LaCourse, D.</author><author>Schwengeler, H.~M.</author><author>Chopin, M.</author><author>Herszkowicz, R.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Planet Hunters. V. A Confirmed Jupiter-size Planet in the Habitable Zone and 42 Planet Candidates from the Kepler Archive Data</title><secondary-title>\apj</secondary-title></titles><volume>776</volume><pages>10</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>October</date></pub-dates></dates><label>wan13</label><keywords><keyword>planets and satellites: detection, techniques: photometric, techniques: radial velocities, techniques: spectroscopic, surveys</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/wang2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0004-637X/776/1/10</url><url>http://arXiv.org/abs/1301.0644</url><url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013ApJ...776...10W</url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0004-637X/776/1/10</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We report the latest Planet Hunter results, including PH2 b, a Jupiter-size (R PL = 10.12 $\pm$ 0.56 R ⊕) planet orbiting in the habitable zone of a solar-type star. PH2 b was elevated from candidate status when a series of false-positive tests yielded a 99.9% confidence level that transit events detected around the star KIC 12735740 had a planetary origin. Planet Hunter volunteers have also discovered 42 new planet candidates in the Kepler public archive data, of which 33 have at least 3 transits recorded. Most of these transit candidates have orbital periods longer than 100 days and 20 are potentially located in the habitable zones of their host stars. Nine candidates were detected with only two transit events and the prospective periods are longer than 400 days. The photometric models suggest that these objects have radii that range between those of Neptune and Jupiter. These detections nearly double the number of gas-giant planet candidates orbiting at habitable-zone distances. We conducted spectroscopic observations for nine of the brighter targets to improve the stellar parameters and we obtained adaptive optics imaging for four of the stars to search for blended background or foreground stars that could confuse our photometric modeling. We present an iterative analysis method to derive the stellar and planet properties and uncertainties by combining the available spectroscopic parameters, stellar evolution models, and transiting light curve parameters, weighted by the measurement errors. Planet Hunters is a citizen science project that crowd sources the assessment of NASA Kepler light curves. The discovery of these 43 planet candidates demonstrates the success of citizen scientists at identifying planet candidates, even in longer period orbits with only two or three transit events.  .</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>02/10/2013</added-date><modified-date>02/10/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>518</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Way, M.~J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo Morphology and Photometric Redshifts in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey</title><secondary-title>\apjl</secondary-title></titles><volume>734</volume><pages>L9</pages><dates><year>2011</year><pub-dates><date>June</date></pub-dates></dates><label>way11</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: distances and redshifts, methods: statistical</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/way2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/2041-8205/734/1/L9</electronic-resource-num><abstract>It has recently been demonstrated that one can accurately derive galaxy morphology from particular primary and secondary isophotal shape estimates in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS) imaging catalog. This was accomplished by applying Machine Learning techniques to the Galaxy Zoo morphology catalog. Using the broad bandpass photometry of the SDSS in combination with precise knowledge of galaxy morphology should help in estimating more accurate photometric redshifts for galaxies. Using the Galaxy Zoo separation for spirals and ellipticals in combination with SDSS photometry we attempt to calculate photometric redshifts. In the best case we find that the root-mean-square error for luminous red galaxies classified as ellipticals is as low as 0.0118. Given these promising results we believe better photometric redshift estimates for all galaxies in the SDSS (~350 million) will be feasible if researchers can also leverage their derived morphologies via Machine Learning. These initial results look to be promising for those interested in estimating weak lensing, baryonic acoustic oscillation, and other fields dependent upon accurate photometric redshifts.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>25</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Willett, K.~W.</author><author>Lintott, C.~J.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Simmons, B.~D.</author><author>Casteels, K.~R.~V.</author><author>Edmondson, E.~M.</author><author>Fortson, L.~F.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Melvin, T.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Simpson, R.~J.</author><author>Skibba, R.~A.</author><author>Smith, A.~M.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo 2: detailed morphological classifications for 304 122 galaxies from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>435</volume><pages>2835-2860</pages><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>November</date></pub-dates></dates><label>wil13</label><keywords><keyword>methods: data analysis, catalogues, galaxies: elliptical and lenticular, galaxies: general, galaxies: spiral</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/willett2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/mnras/stt1458</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present the data release for Galaxy Zoo 2 (GZ2), a citizen science project with more than 16 million morphological classifications of 304 122 galaxies drawn from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS). Morphology is a powerful probe for quantifying a galaxy&apos;s dynamical history; however, automatic classifications of morphology (either by computer analysis of images or by using other physical parameters as proxies) still have drawbacks when compared to visual inspection. The large number of images available in current surveys makes visual inspection of each galaxy impractical for individual astronomers. GZ2 uses classifications from volunteer citizen scientists to measure morphologies for all galaxies in the DR7 Legacy survey with mr &gt; 17, in addition to deeper images from SDSS Stripe 82. While the original GZ2 project identified galaxies as early-types, late-types or mergers, GZ2 measures finer morphological features. These include bars, bulges and the shapes of edge-on disks, as well as quantifying the relative strengths of galactic bulges and spiral arms. This paper presents the full public data release for the project, including measures of accuracy and bias. The majority (≳90 per cent) of GZ2 classifications agree with those made by professional astronomers, especially for morphological T-types, strong bars and arm curvature. Both the raw and reduced data products can be obtained in electronic format at http://data.galaxyzoo.org.</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>17/10/2013</added-date><modified-date>17/10/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>520</rec-number><ref-type>17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wong, O.~I.</author><author>Schawinski, K.</author><author>Kaviraj, S.</author><author>Masters, K.~L.</author><author>Nichol, R.~C.</author><author>Lintott, C.</author><author>Keel, W.~C.</author><author>Darg, D.</author><author>Bamford, S.~P.</author><author>Andreescu, D.</author><author>Murray, P.</author><author>Raddick, M.~J.</author><author>Szalay, A.</author><author>Thomas, D.</author><author>Vandenberg, J.</author></authors><secondary-authors></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Galaxy Zoo: building the low-mass end of the red sequence with local post-starburst galaxies</title><secondary-title>\mnras</secondary-title></titles><volume>420</volume><pages>1684-1692</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>February</date></pub-dates></dates><label>won12</label><keywords><keyword>galaxies: evolution</keyword></keywords><urls><pdf-urls><url>file://localhost/Users/willettk/Papers/wong2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.20159.x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present a study of local post-starburst galaxies (PSGs) using the photometric and spectroscopic observations from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and the results from the Galaxy Zoo project. We find that the majority of our local PSG population have neither early- nor late-type morphologies but occupy a well-defined space within the colour-stellar mass diagram, most notably, the low-mass end of the &apos;green valley&apos; below the transition mass thought to be the mass division between low-mass star-forming galaxies and high-mass passively evolving bulge-dominated galaxies. Our analysis suggests that it is likely that local PSGs will quickly transform into &apos;red&apos;, low-mass early-type galaxies as the stellar morphologies of the &apos;green&apos; PSGs largely resemble that of the early-type galaxies within the same mass range. We propose that the current population of PSGs represents a population of galaxies which is rapidly transitioning between the star-forming and the passively evolving phases. Subsequently, these PSGs will contribute towards the build-up of the low-mass end of the &apos;red sequence&apos; once the current population of young stars fade and stars are no longer being formed. These results are consistent with the idea of &apos;downsizing&apos; where the build-up of smaller galaxies occurs at later epochs. This publication has been made possible by the participation of more than 250 000 volunteers in the Galaxy Zoo project. Their contributions are individually acknowledged at .</abstract><custom3>article</custom3><added-date>29/11/2012</added-date><modified-date>22/02/2013</modified-date></record>
<record><database name="kwrefs.bib" path="/Users/willettk/Library/texmf/bibtex/bib/kwrefs.bib">kwrefs.bib</database><source-app name="BibDesk" version="1.6.1">BibDesk</source-app><rec-number>400</rec-number><ref-type>5</ref-type><contributors><authors></authors><secondary-authors><author>Brusuelas, James</author></secondary-authors><subsidiary-authors></subsidiary-authors></contributors><titles><title>The Oxyrhynchus Papyri</title><tertiary-title>P.Oxy 5156</tertiary-title></titles><volume>78</volume><edition>Quaestiones Convivales IV PR., 1.2</edition><section>660C, 661B-C</section><publisher>Egypt Exploration Society</publisher><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates></pub-dates></dates><label>bru13</label><keywords></keywords><urls><pdf-urls></pdf-urls><related-urls></related-urls></urls><custom3>inbook</custom3><added-date>16/08/2013</added-date><modified-date>22/08/2013</modified-date></record>
</records>
</xml>
